- 1863 Tibet -
You've done well to endure the hardships of
your training for the past three years.
(ﾄﾝﾍﾟﾃｨ)《３年間
ここの荒行に よくぞ耐えた｡➡
If you so desired, you could run
across the land without losing a single breath.
今のそなたは 呼吸を乱さず
何十里も 走ることができよう｡➡
Normally, we would begin to move into the final stage of training, instructing you in the most advanced Ripple techniques...
いよいよ
これから ｢周天の法門｣という➡
高度の修行に入るが
もう一度 言うぞ ツェペリ｡➡
But I must warn you one last time, Zeppeli...
このまま 修行を続けるなら
もう抜け出られん｡➡
If you continue along this path, there will be no escaping the fate I have foreseen for you.
そなたの 死の運命から｡➡
This is your last chance to turn back.
Doing so will allow you to take a different path.
やめるなら 今じゃ｡
やめれば 新しい道も開けよう》
Master Tompetty...
(ﾂｪﾍﾟﾘ)《老師 トンペティ｡➡
Elder, please... tell me the destiny my life force reveals...
詳しく 読んでください
私の 生命の波調を➡
...about my fated death.
私の死への運命を｡➡
When will it happen? Where will it take place?
いつなのですか？
どこなのですか？》
What good will come of knowing this?
(ﾄﾝﾍﾟﾃｨ)《知ってどうする？》
I have a task that I must be able to complete...
《私には 追い求めているものが
あるのです｡➡
A duty that I cannot turn my back on...
それを
放っておくことはできません｡
Knowing will allow me to stay true to that goal.
自分の生きざまを 全うするために
知りたいのです》
Once I know the time of my death,
I can make peace with the outcome.
《私は
自分の死期を知ったところで➡
全てを 受け入れます》
《全てに 満足します》
Then I will accept my fate.
If you are truly this determined...
《そこまでの覚悟があるならば
教えよう！》
...then so be it!
In an ancient chamber, hidden from view, and heavy with the stench of death...
《古からの 死臭漂う 密室で➡
...a child will reveal the way.
幼子が 門を開くとき！➡
In order to set a young lion free, you will incur a mortal injury...
鎖でつながれた 若き獅子を
未来へ 解き放つため➡
おのが自身は その傷を燃やし➡
And then, you will be clenched in the cruel grip of death!
しかるのちに
残酷な死を 迎えるであろう！》
Old man Zeppeli...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ツェペリのおっさん…｡
気を付けろよ おっさん！
Be careful, old man!
(ﾂｪﾍﾟﾘ)ふぅ～…｡
Here I come, Jojo!
行くぞ ジョジョ！
Now I must set that young lion free... Onwards, to his destiny!
《鎖でつながれた 若き獅子を
未来へ 解き放つため！》
♬(ｵｰﾌﾟﾆﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
Sora koboreochita futatsu no hoshi ga
Two stars fall from the sky
♬ 空 こぼれ落ちたふたつの星が
Original Translation:
Mudasubs
Hikari to yami no minamo suikomareteyuku
One shining in the light, the other sinking into darkness
♬ 光と闇の水面
吸い込まれてゆく
Hikiau you ni kasanaru hamon
A ripple drawing the two of them together
♬ 引き合うように 重なる波紋
♬～
Editor:
Chonichonitoptop
Distro:
ExWizzard
Editor:
Chonichonitoptop
Distro:
ExWizzard
Editor:
Chonichonitoptop
Distro:
ExWizzard
Editor:
Chonichonitoptop
Distro:
ExWizzard
Editor:
Chonichonitoptop
Distro:
ExWizzard
Editor:
Chonichonitoptop
Distro:
ExWizzard
Hokori no michi wo yuku mono ni taiyou no michibiki wo
One will walk the path of pride and receive the sun's guidance
♬ 誇りの道を往く者に
太陽の導きを
Yabou no hate wo mezasu mono ni
One will walk the path of unbridled ambition...
♬ 野望の果てを目指す者に
生け贄を
Ikenie wo
Demanding sacrifice!
♬～
Furueru hodo kokoro moetsukiru hodo atsuku
Let that burning in your soul calm the trembling of your heart
♬ 震えるほど心
燃え尽きるほど熱く
Timing/Typesetting/Encoding:
Fadeout4
Sono te kara hanate kodou
Strike down your fears,
♬ その手から放て 鼓動
Karada minagiru yuuki de
With courage coursing through your veins!
♬ 身体 漲る勇気で
Mayou naki kakugo ni kassai wo
You cannot overcome your pain unless you can accept...
♬ 迷いなき覚悟に喝采を
Raw Hunter:
WRRRRY
Sono chi no sadame
The legacy of your bloodline!
♬ その血の運命 ジョジョ
Jojo!
♬～
http://www.some-stuffs.com/
Episode 7: "Sorrowful Successor"
(ｼﾞｮﾅｻﾝ)《くっ…
この首輪 びくともしない｡➡
This collar won't even budge...
それに
タルカスは まだ見せていない｡➡
...and I still haven't seen Tarkus use this room to his full advantage!
この 殺人修練場の
特質を生かした戦法を！➡
It's eerie!
その点が不気味！》
Make your move, worm!
(ﾀﾙｶｽ)来い てめえら！
I know you're itching to unleash your Ripple on me!
波紋とやらを わしに送りたいか？
ふぬけどもにゃ 指１本とて
わしに触れることはできん！
A wretch like you won't even be able to lay a finger on me!
む？
What's the matter? Lost your nerve?!
どうした？ おじけづいたか!?
ていっ！
コォー…｡
Way to go, old man Zeppeli!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)
いいぞ ツェペリのおっさん！
ぬん！
ぬあ～！
ぬおおおおお！
おりゃぁぁ！ 食らえ タルカス！
Take this, Tarkus!
Tornado Overdrive!
トルネーディオーバードライブ！
ううっ こ… これは!?
W-What the-?!
う… 上からか!?
From above!
No, Mr. Zeppeli! The chain is coming from below you!
違う ツェペリさん！
下から鎖が！
うっ！
上と下からの 同時攻撃！
An attack that closes in from above and below!
うおおっ！
This is my deathblow; the Hell and Heaven Snake Kill!
必殺技 ヘルヘブンスネーキル！
ぐあっ！
うぐっ！
なっ！
ううっ…｡
(ﾀﾙｶｽ)
グフフフ｡ ２人同時に 絞め殺す！
Now I'll crush you both to death!
ぐううっ！
ううっ…｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)うう…｡
I-If I can't breathe... I can't use... the Ripple...
《い… 息ができん…｡
これでは 波紋が…》
ぐるっ ぐるっ！
ああ…｡
ああ… ああ…｡
うぐっ…｡
ああ…｡
うわあ～！
あ… あ…｡
Jo...
ジョ… ジョジョ…｡
Jojo...
ディオ様
命令どおり 始末いたしました｡
Master Dio...
...I have disposed of them, as you wished.
こ… こんな！
こんなこと 残酷すぎる！
This was... This was far too cruel!
うああ～！
ん！ ぬぅ…｡
うっ… ううっ…｡
あっ！ ジョースターさん！
Mr. Joestar!
うっ…｡
ウヌゥ～…｡
So you're still alive, even with a broken neck?
首の骨が折れたのに
まだ息があるのか この若造｡
Time to put you out of your misery!
とどめを刺してくれる！
むう… ぬぬう！
Jo... Jojo!
ジョ… ジョジョ…｡
ぬう～
こやつも まだ生きているのか｡
This one is also still going?!
My ultimate...
我が 究極の…｡
...This is my ultimate...
This is my ultimate technique! I'm passing it on to you, Jojo!
我が 究極の奥義
ジョジョに ささげる！
Jojo... please... inherit my will!
ジョジョ 継いでくれ！
わしの意志を！
究極！
ディーパスオーバードライブ！
Ultimate Deep Pass Overdrive!
うがあっ！
あ～！
ぬぉぉぉぉぉぉ！
あ… ああ…｡
ふぬ～っ！
フフ… ジョジョ…｡
Jojo... I'm passing down all of my life energy to you...
私の 生命エネルギー
全てを ささげたぞ…｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)うう…｡
お… おっさん｡
O-Old man...
ツェ… ツェペリのおっさん！
Old man Zeppeli!
ああ～！
てめえら ２人とも
わしの足底で ズタボロと化せ！
I'm going to smash the two of you to a pulp beneath my feet!
ぐっ！
はっ…｡
H-How the hell-?!
こ… こいつ…｡
M-Mr. Joestar... lifted up Tarkus?!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ジョースターさんが
タルカスを つり上げた！➡
Old man Zeppeli's Ripple must have healed his broken neck!
ツェペリのおっさんの波紋が
首の骨を 治癒したんだ！
ヌハハ！ まぬけ！
You fool! You're really trying to remove that collar by force?!
その首輪を 引きちぎる気か！
人間の てめえがか!?
You're just a mere mortal man!
You're trying to break steel that even I couldn't break,
even with the power granted to me by Master Dio!
ディオ様に 力を授かった➡
このわしでさえ
手こずる鋼鉄をよ！
ぬぅぅぅぅっ！
うぉぉぉぉぉ！
許さん！ タルカス！
You will pay, Tarkus!
なっ!?
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ジョースターさん！
Mr. Joestar!
ぐあ！ な… 何!? GAYN！
W-What?!
Your twisted mind... that hideous madness of yours...
その ゆがんだ精神｡
醜悪なる狂気｡
心の奥底まで
魂を ディオに売り渡したな？
You willingly surrendered the depths of your mortal soul to Dio, haven't you?
ぐっ…｡
Wrrrrryyyyyy!
GYYY!? YYA！
コォー…｡
URRRRRYYYYY！
ぬおおお！
ANGYAAAAH！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)つ… 強い！
ほとばしるほど 強い！➡
He's strong!
He's incredibly strong!
今までの
ジョースターさんと違う！
He isn't the same Mr. Joestar he was before!
The Ripple of old man Zeppeli's life force is flowing right through him!
《ツェペリのおっさんの
生命波紋が宿ったんだ！》
《２人の力の 相乗作用！》
This is the strength of their power combined!
タルカス… お前の骨 １つとて
この世に残さん！
Tarkus... Not a single bone of yours will be left when I'm done with you.
I'm going to exorcise that wicked soul of yours!
邪悪な魂を絶ってやる！
ギギギギ…｡
Fade back... into the shadows of history!
歴史の闇に 永遠に沈め！
I've had enough of your insolence, whelp!
ほざけ てめえ こわっぱが！
プッ！
うりゃあ！
So you're resorting to petty tricks?!
小細工に堕したか！
WWWRRRRYYYYーッ!!
おおおお！
はああっ！
決まった！
He got him!
ツェペリさん！
Mr. Zeppeli!
Mr. Zeppeli...
はぁ… はぁ…｡
This... This can't be...
こんな… こんなことって…｡
あなたが いなくなったら…｡
If you're gone...
あなたが いなくなったら
僕らは どうすればいいのですか!?
If you're gone... what are we going to do?!
Jojo, you...
ジョジョ… 貴様… 大バカ者が！
You damned idiot!
Now is not the time to mourn!
悲しんどる場合か！
You... you still have to...
い… 今のお前は…｡
Now, there's no time to lose...
さあ 早く行け｡
You must must go and defeat Dio.
ディオを倒すのだ｡
Destroy... the stone mask...
石仮面を 破壊するのだ｡ ゴホッ！
ツェペリさん！
Mr. Zeppeli!
(ポコ)あっ… ううっ…｡
I'm... satisfied with the way... my destiny played out.
わしは…
自分の運命に 満足しておるよ｡
わしは… 若いころ 結婚していた｡
When I was a young man... I was married...
しかし…
石仮面のため 家族を捨てた｡
However... I abandoned my family for the quest to destroy the stone mask...
But now, I can rest in peace being satisfied with the life I led...
だけども…
自分の運命に 満足しておる｡
I can accept what has become of me...
全てを 受け入れておるよ｡
In the end... at least I was able to pass on all that I had...
わしは 最後に
自分の全てを伝えた｡
Jojo.... you are my living hope.
ジョジョ… お前は わしの希望だ｡
Mr. Zeppeli...
ツェペリさん…｡
I think of you as my best friend and son...
まるで 親友と息子を
同時に 持ったような気持ちだぞ｡
そして わしは これから
お前の中で 生きるんじゃ…｡
...and... I will continue... to live on...
...within you...
Jo...
(ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)〈19世紀 イギリスの作家
ｳｨﾘｱﾑ･M･ｻｯｶﾚｰは言った〉
In the words of 19th century novelist William M. Thackeray...
〈｢愛して その人を得ることは
最上である｣〉
"To love and win is the best thing."
"To love and lose, the next best."
〈｢愛して その人を失うことは
その次に良い｣と〉
And so, once again, Jojo finds himself inheriting another man's way of life... and his very spirit.
〈そして
ジョジョは また受け継ぐ｡➡
彼の生き方と その精神を〉
Goodbye... Mr. Zeppeli.
《さよなら ツェペリさん…》
(女性)うう… お… お願いです｡
I-I'm begging you...
Please... Please, just spare my child...
(女性)どうか… どうか
この子の命だけは お助けを…｡
うう…｡
(ﾃﾞｨｵ)
ん～ するというと ミセス➡
Let me see if I understand your request, Miss...
あなたは
こう 希望しているわけだ｡
You do not mind what happens to you, so long as we do not harm your child?
｢自分の命は
我々に 献上してもいいが➡
子供には
手を かけないでほしい｣と｡
そうかね？
Is that correct?
ひっ…！
この子だけは… お… お願いです｡
Just spare my child... I beg of you!
How heartwarming!
泣けるじゃあないか｡
Okay... Neither I, nor my men, will bring any harm to that infant.
ＯＫ！ 私と 彼ら全員➡
誰も その子に
決して 手をかけることはしない｡
このディオ 誓おうではないか｡
I, Dio, swear this to you.
But, if I may... The men you see around you have all given in to their fear, and so they offered their souls to me in my greatness.
だがね
ここにいる しもべたちは➡
恐怖に屈し 自ら進んで
魂を このディオにささげたが…｡
You and your child would be much happier if you both joined us, I assure you.
こいつらのように➡
親子２人で 我らの
仲間になった方が 幸福だぞ｡
You would be free from from worry and pain...
Your family would be absolved of all hatred!
悩みも 苦しみも➡
親子で 憎しみ合うことも
決して なくなるのだ｡
この子だけは お助けください！
Please, spare my child!
Spare him...
(女性)この子だけは…｡
ＯＫ！ ＯＫ！
Okay, okay.
(血を吸う音)
(赤ん坊の泣き声)
My... My baby!
私の 赤ちゃん！
As I promised, my men and I have done nothing.
言ったとおり 我々は 手をかけん｡
食い殺すのは 母親の貴様よ｡
Even as his mother, you still devoured him!
自分の選択した
悲劇というわけか｡
A tragedy of your own making...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)
《ジョースターさんの顔つきが
変わったようだ…》
Mr. Joestar's face has changed...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)
《表情に 影が濃くなった》
He has a very brooding look on his face...
The same goes for me...
《俺だって 同じよ…｡➡
悲しみと怒りを
必死に こらえている｡➡
I'm just barely able to hold back the anger and sadness!
Even so, until Dio has been defeated, we can't afford to mope!
だが あのディオを倒すまでは
悲しんじゃあいられねえ！》
ジョースターさん｡
ディオのやつは さっき➡
Mr. Joestar! Dio said he was planning to wipe this town out by tomorrow!
｢一昼夜中に
この町を全滅させる｣と言った！
Zombies will give rise to more zombies!  They'll breed like rats!
ゾンビは ゾンビを生み➡
その早さは ねずみ算だぜ！
うん｡
How are they holding up over there?
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)
一体 町はどうなっているんだ？➡
Are the people of Wind Knights' Lot still alive?!
ウインドナイツ･ロットは
まだ 生きているのか？
I hope my sister and the others are okay...
姉ちゃんたち 大丈夫かな…｡
Let's hurry...
急ごう！
あっ！ アダムスさん！
Mr. Adams!
Hey, Poco! Where have you been, wandering off at this hour?
(ｱﾀﾞﾑｽ)おい ポコ！ こんな夜遅く
どこ ほっつき歩いとるんだ!?
アダムスさん！
おいらの姉ちゃんは？
Mr. Adams, is my sister all right?!
And what about the town?!
ま… 町は？ だ… 大丈夫？
Is she okay?
｢大丈夫｣だと!?
お前 大丈夫どころか…｡
Kid... she's not all right at all!
She's absolutely livid!
カンカンもんよ！
She said she's gonna lock you up with the cows when you get home!
｢帰ってきたら お前を
牛小屋に 閉じ込める｣とよ！
Well, it looks like the town is safe for now...
町は まだ無事のようだ｡
急ぎやしょう！
Then let's hurry!
(ポコ)
あ… ありがとう アダムスさん！
T-Thank you, Mr. Adams!
A-A child...
(ｱﾀﾞﾑｽ)
こ… 子供だ！ ウヒヒヒ！➡
子供の
あったけえ 血が吸いてえぜ｡
The warm blood of a child is such a treat!
ウヒヒヒ！ ウシャー！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ･ﾎﾟｺ)ああああああっ！
くぅ～！
He was already a zombie!
この男 既にゾンビだ！
ウシャー！
俺様のスピードが かわせるか！
You think you can match my speed?!
ガッ？
コォー…｡
ドギャーッ！
It looks like the town has already been...
この分では 町は もう…｡
Precisely.
≪(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)そのとおりだ！
(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)町外れに
ゾンビが はびこりつつあるぞ｡
The zombies have already surrounded the town...
N-No!
ひ… ひゃあ！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)新手のゾンビか!?
Another zombie?!
My name is Dire.
我が名は ダイアー｡
A kick? But it's so slow...
蹴りか…｡
しかし スローな蹴りだ｡
ぬぅぅぅん！
うおおおおおおっ！
うっ！
(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)必殺！ ｻﾝﾀﾞｰｽﾌﾟﾘｯﾄｱﾀｯｸ！
ぬおっ！ ぐおっ！
W-What an amazing man!
な… なんてやつだ!?➡
Any other man would have flinched to avoid that attack...
普通なら
後方に頭を反らして 逃げるのを➡
...but you attacked with a headbutt,
even though it ended up hurting you!
逆に 負傷覚悟の頭突きで
攻撃してくるとは！
(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)待て！
ジョナサン･ジョースター！➡
Wait, Jonathan Joestar!
I am a human.
私は 人間だ！
Please excuse me for testing the skills you learned from Zeppeli.
失礼だったが➡
君が ツェペリさんから学んだ
実力を 試させてもらったのだ｡
You knew Mr. Zeppeli?!
今 ｢ツェペリさん｣と!?
Yes... Zeppeli and I trained under the same master.
(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)ああ ツェペリさんとは
同じ師の下➡
共に 苦行を乗り越えてきた
20年来の親友だ｡
We underwent the same hardships together,
and have been friends for over 20 years.
≪(ｽﾄﾚｲﾂｫ)いかにも｡
Indeed...
I am Straits... Take a look at this.
私は ストレイツォ｡
これを見たまえ｡
A letter?
手紙か？ 差出人は…｡
It was sent by...
...Mr. Zeppeli!?
ツェペリさん！
Precisely...
(ｽﾄﾚｲﾂｫ)そうだ｡
ツェペリさんが 我々に➡
A letter from Zeppeli, requesting our assistance.
助けを求める文面の手紙だ｡➡
Upon learning the location of the stone mask and the identity of the holder, he sent us the details.
石仮面の行方と それを持つ者を
知った ツェペリさんが➡
全てのことを書いて
送ってよこしたのだ｡
あっ！
This is our master, Tompetty.
(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)
こちらは 我が師 トンペティ｡
(ﾄﾝﾍﾟﾃｨ)はぁ… よろし～く｡
A pleasure to meet you.
You're Mr. Zeppeli's master... The elder, Tompetty.
あなたが ツェペリさんの師匠
老師 トンペティ｡
ん～？
ん？
We do not share the same customs, you see...
我々には
そのような習慣はなくてな…｡
This is how we greet one another.
これが 挨拶じゃ｡
So, where is Zeppeli?
ところで… ツェペリはどこかな？
I see, then Zeppeli has already passed on...
(ﾄﾝﾍﾟﾃｨ)そうか…
ツェペリのやつ 逝きおったか｡
(ﾄﾝﾍﾟﾃｨ)我々が
今少し 早く 着いたとしても➡
Even if we had arrived sooner, his fate would not have changed...
同じ運命じゃったろう…｡
I must say, this Dio exudes a very unnerving power...
(ﾄﾝﾍﾟﾃｨ)それにしても
その ディオとかいう男➡
圧倒的かな！
He life force is incredibly malevolent!
すさまじい
悪の生命力を持つやつよ！
フフ… この町➡
In little more than a night, this town now entirely belongs to me...
一夜かからんうちに
俺のものだな｡
フッ｡
♬(ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
♬ I'll be the roundabout
I'll be the roundabout
♬ The words
will make you out'n'out
The words will make you out 'n' out
♬ I spend the day away
I'll spend the day your way
Call it morning driving through the sound and
♬ Call it morning
driving through
♬ the sound and
in and out the valley
In and out the valley
♬～
♬ The music dance and sing
The music dance and sing
♬ They make
the children really ring
They make the children really ring
♬ Spend the day away
I'll spend the day your way
♬ Call it morning
driving through
Call it morning driving through the sound and
♬ the sound and
in and out the valley
In and out the valley
♬ In and around the lake
In and around the lake
♬ Mountains come out of
the sky and they stand there
Mountains come out of the sky
and they stand there
♬ One mile over we'll be there
and we'll see you
One mile over we'll be there and we'll see you
♬ Ten true summers
Ten true summers we'll be there and laughing too
♬ we'll be there
and laughing too
♬ Twenty four before
my love you'll see
Twenty-four before my love you'll see I'll be
♬ I'll be there with you
There with you
Next Episode
You fell for it, fool!
I, Straits, will show no mercy!
I feel no guilt putting an end to you!
Come, Jojo!
Episode 8:
"Jojo & Dio's Bloody Battle!"
(ﾄﾞｩｰﾋﾞｰ)ルン ルン ルン！
(ﾀﾞｲｱｰ)かかったな アホが！
(ｽﾄﾚｲﾂｫ)
このストレイツォ 容赦せん！
お前を葬るのに 罪悪感なし！
来い！ ジョジョ！